Roshan Rahman

🗣 Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India 🗷 roshanrahman6399@gmail.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/roshanrahman6399/ 🕳 roshanroshan.me

SUMMARY

Passionate about making well designed products, and have experience crafting simple, coherent and user friendly interfaces. Designed (and developed) websites, mobile apps, and have experienced the curious life of a freelancer.

Passionate about making well designed products, and have experience crafting simple, coherent and user friendly interfaces. Designed (and developed) websites, mobile apps, and have experienced the curious life of a freelancer.

EXPERIENCE

Product Engineer Trainee (Backend) | Codingmart Technologies | Coimbatore | December 2019 - Present

- Built microservices in Golang that introduced new features that the existing use cases can consumed. Built architecture from scratch, and carried over my design skills to better understand the use cases and design the architecture to develop the best fitting, scalable solution.
- Built several projects involving popular web technologies, including Django, React and Angular. Developed a hospital appointment booking system in Django supporting OAuth, E-mail verification and reminders, multiple users and a zero-framework frontend built with plain, scratch CSS that boosted my CSS layout and design skills.
- Built microservices in Golang that introduced new features that the existing use cases can consumed. Built architecture from scratch, and carried over my design skills to better understand the use cases and design the architecture to develop the best fitting, scalable solution.
- $\cdot \ Built several projects involving popular web technologies, including Django, React and Angular. Developed a hospital appointment booking system in Django supporting OAuth, E-mail verification and reminders, multiple users and a zero-framework frontend built with plain, scratch CSS that boosted my CSS layout and design skills.$

UX Designer & Frontend Developer | Freelance (Electronics startup) | Coimbatore | September 2019 - December 2019

- Designed mobile applications for a local e-commerce startup to deliver solutions that offered great user experience. Collaborated with the startup founders to construct the branding and design system. Supported the developers throughout the project as a UX Designer and taking additional tasks such as testing and writing Flutter components.
- Built and implemented an integral part of the platform: a robust, responsive web portal in Vue.js and Vuetify that allowed sellers to dispatch orders, manage inventory, run ad campaigns and view reports of their income.
- Designed mobile applications for a local e-commerce startup to deliver solutions that offered great user experience. Collaborated with the startup founders to construct the branding and design system. Supported the developers throughout the project as a UX Designer and taking additional tasks such as testing and writing Flutter components.
- Built and implemented an integral part of the platform: a robust, responsive web portal in Vue. js and Vuetify that allowed sellers to dispatch orders, manage inventory, run ad campaigns and view reports of their income.

UX Designer | Freelance (Shiksha Foundation) | Coimbatore | February 2020

Created

- a digital alternative option to paper based forms for the process of collecting donations for children's education. Explored ideas to increase donor trust and insight into the organization's actions. Designed a mobile application for use by donation-collecting volunteers.
- Supported the developers throughout the project, and used Adobe XD to build prototypes of the interface.
- Created a digital alternative option to paper based forms for the process of collecting donations for children's education. Explored ideas to increase donor trust and insight into the organization's actions. Designed a mobile application for use by donation-collecting volunteers.
- · Supported the developers throughout the project, and used Adobe XD to build prototypes of the interface.

Research / Usability Testing Intern | Baduga (bluCursor Technologies) | Remote | July 2018 - August 2018

- Contributed detailed feedback on the application's performance and usability, and helped make it more robust and user friendly. Improved navigation by making content properly categorised.
- Collaborated with the project's lead to help improve user experience, and designed mock-ups to suggest usability improvements in the interface.
- · Contributed detailed feedback on the application's performance and usability, and helped make it more robust and user friendly. Improved navigation by making content properly categorised.
- · Collaborated with the project's lead to help improve user experience, and designed mock-ups to suggest usability improvements in the interface.

PROJECTS

- Designed and prototyped an elegant, simple, easy to use interface for a notes taking application, with emphasis on strong typography and new visual design trends.
- \cdot Developed the app in Flutter, using SQFlite to store the notes locally, with features to enhance user experience, such as smooth animations and theme customization.
- \cdot Designed and prototyped an elegant, simple, easy to use interface for a notes taking application, with emphasis on strong typography and new visual design trends.
- $\cdot \text{ Developed the app in Flutter, using SQFlite to store the notes locally, with features to enhance user experience, such as smooth animations and theme customization.}$

CS Entry - A Mark Entry & Processing System | Team Project | January 2019 - March 2019

- Designed and prototyped the user interface for the mobile version, and supported the developers throughout the project encompassing 3 months until its deployment to over 30 staff members, handling marks of over 300 students.
- Built the web version of this project that allows teachers to enter marks and generate reports automatically, reducing staff's work time from hours to seconds. Significantly reduced the time taken to accomplish the tasks by 96%, by automating the entire process.
- Designed and prototyped the user interface for the mobile version, and supported the developers throughout the project encompassing 3 months until its deployment to over 30 staff members, handling marks of over 300 students.
- Built the web version of this project that allows teachers to enter marks and generate reports automatically, reducing staff's work time from hours to seconds. Significantly reduced the time taken to accomplish the tasks by 96%, by automating the entire process.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science & Engineering | SNS College Of Technology | Coimbatore, India | 2020

SKILLS

UX Design: Interface Design, Figma, Adobe XD, Prototyping

UX Design: Interface Design, Figma, Adobe XD, Prototyping

Front End: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, React & Vue

Front End: HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, React & Vue

Programming: Flutter (Dart), Django, Python, Golang

Programming: Flutter (Dart), Django, Python, Golang